Neugass, Fritz; Papers ger007
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Photographs by Fritz Neugass, 1950s-1979; 14; 164 file folders
  - Photographs, 14.1
    - Mexico (1-3), Undated (Box 35 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 9-11)
      - A boat dock scene, with a line of people on the..., ca. 1953
      - A boy running in the middle of an alley, with..., ca. 1953
      - The back of people kneeling and worshipping. The..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - A packed banquet hall scene of well dressed men..., ca. 1953
      - A man wearing a hat, holding a cigarette, sitting..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - A woman with her shawl wrapped around her head,..., ca. 1953
      - Two young men in tunics and hats sitting on a..., ca. 1953
      - An older woman sits next to a younger woman..., ca. 1953
      - A woman in a white skirt sitting with a young girl..., ca. 1953
      - A woman in a white skirt sitting with a young girl..., ca. 1953
      - A young man wearing a white hat and shirt..., ca. 1953
      - A woman wearing a striped tunic...., ca. 1953
      - A man riding a bicycle with two large baskets..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - The American Museum of Natural History in 1954..., ca. 1953
      - Two young girls eating snacks...., ca. 1953
      - Three Mariachi muscians with guitars singing into..., ca. 1953
      - The back of a man with a backpack and hat, holding..., ca. 1953
      - A boy carrying a chicken under his arm stands next..., ca. 1953
      - Small ground of people standing in hay, as one man..., ca. 1953
      - Two ox attached to a wooden beam at the horns,..., ca. 1953
      - A old woman with a black shawl over her head,..., ca. 1953
      - Women selling food against the side of a building...., ca. 1953
      - Three young girls on a horse, posing for a..., ca. 1953
      - A man wearing a hat dressed in Charro attire...., ca. 1953
    - Mexico (4-8), Undated (Box 36 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 1-5)
      - Convertible car parked on the street next to a..., ca. 1953
      - Woman with a baby on her back next to a straw..., ca. 1953
      - Four men standing outside an entryway with shawls...., ca. 1953
      - Ruins of a structure with bushes viewed from under..., ca. 1953
      - Three men bundling up pottery with straw...., ca. 1953
      - Stone structure of two bells hung under arches...., ca. 1953
      - Two tall buildings under construction...., ca. 1953
      - Bell in the bell tower hung under an arch...., ca. 1953
      - Smaller stepped structures at Teotihuacan...., ca. 1953
      - White modern-designed church that has a façade..., ca. 1953
      - Church façade with ornate entry and three bells on..., ca. 1953
      - Portrait of an old man with a hat and shawl draped..., ca. 1953
      - Two men with floral wreaths and crosses...., ca. 1953
      - A white church with people walking out of it...., ca. 1953
      - Stone structure of two bells hung under arches...., ca. 1953
      - Straw baskets stacked in a pyramid...., ca. 1953
      - A young man wearing a hat, and white shirt sitting..., ca. 1953
      - A woman draped in dark clothing, with her hair..., ca. 1953
      - A girl carrying a baby on her back standing on the..., ca. 1953
      - A group of five men in hats (some standing, one..., ca. 1953
      - Four children: two girls stand in the back row,..., ca. 1953
      - Three boys wearing hats, carrying sacks on their..., ca. 1953
      - A cobbled street with two women, three men, and a..., ca. 1953
      - Two young men in tunics and hats at the market..., ca. 1953
      - A group of four children, one older and three..., ca. 1953
      - Two boys in shawls and hats sitting next to a..., ca. 1953
      - A ruin structure with three brick chimneys...., ca. 1953
      - An old man with a hat and shawl draped over his..., ca. 1953
      - A girl in dress holding a small white package..., ca. 1953
      - Three women wrapped in shawls sitting on the..., ca. 1953
      - "Ruins of a hacienda destroyed" with a cow in the..., ca. 1953
      - Man draped in wool with a sword slung over his..., ca. 1953
      - A girl standing in the street next to small..., ca. 1953
      - Fog in a mountain valley with trees and shrubs in..., ca. 1953
      - Two young men in flat straw hats sitting on..., ca. 1953
      - A dock and lake at sunrise. "Sunrise at Janitzio..., ca. 1953
      - Girl washing clothes in shallow waters, at the..., ca. 1953
      - A shore scene with men tending to a boat with a..., ca. 1953
      - Four young men in hats standing on a dusty gravel..., ca. 1953
      - Four men in white shirts and hats squatting down..., ca. 1953
      - Two men holding their hats in their hand walking..., ca. 1953
      - Two men in white garb and flat straw hats walking...., ca. 1953
      - Neighborhood scene with men, women, a small child,..., ca. 1953
      - Men and women in front of a building on Calle..., ca. 1953
      - Two young boys in hats holding thin wooden rods...., ca. 1953
      - Two men, a woman, and a child at church...., ca. 1953
      - A woman vendor, wearing a white tunic, sitting..., ca. 1953
      - A man wearing a hat, stands in the road holding a..., ca. 1953
      - Two young men in tunics and hats sitting on a..., ca. 1953
      - An ox cart in the street with two ox and people..., ca. 1953
      - An old woman wearing a black shawl around her..., ca. 1953
      - A woman with two small children. The woman has her..., ca. 1953
      - A man and two donkeys with wooden barrels strapped..., ca. 1953
      - An old man and young girl at a market stall. The..., ca. 1953
      - A boy leaning against a wooden door, next to him..., ca. 1953
      - Two women in dresses learning near the windows and..., ca. 1953
      - A group of three boys walking outside a school. In..., ca. 1953
      - A woman standing in a small group laughing, next..., ca. 1953
      - A man with a flat straw hat and sheathed blade..., ca. 1953
      - Fisherman in a small fishing boat, handling..., ca. 1953
      - Three young women at a table stand with fruit and..., ca. 1953
      - A vista with trees in the foreground...., ca. 1953
      - A young man with a hat sitting...., ca. 1953
      - A crowd of women and a few men standing on the..., ca. 1953
      - A neighborhood scene with people in the streets..., ca. 1953
      - A young boy wearing a hat holding a key by a metal..., ca. 1953
      - A man and a young boy in a cart pulled by two..., ca. 1953
      - A man squatting on a curb wearing white garb with..., ca. 1953
      - Two young boys, one in a hat, holding straw..., ca. 1953
      - Four men with guitars and a small child at ease in..., ca. 1953
      - A young boy in white wearing a hat standing next..., ca. 1953
      - A man hauling a basket of pottery on his back, in..., ca. 1953
      - A old woman in an apron holding a long stick with..., ca. 1953
      - A woman and a girl with a large basket covering..., ca. 1953
      - Young boy leaning on a tree with a stick in his..., ca. 1953
      - Woman with basket of flowers on balanced on her..., ca. 1953
      - Three women wrapped in shawls sitting on the..., ca. 1953
      - A man and young man with sacks, wearing hats at..., ca. 1953
      - Shucked corncobs with four lit taper candles...., ca. 1953
      - Men loading stuff onto a donkey's back...., ca. 1953
      - A boy leaning against a wooden door holding some..., ca. 1953
      - Women washing clothes outside in stone basins,..., ca. 1953
      - Four women wrapped in shawls sitting on the ground..., ca. 1953
      - A man down on one knee, with his hat off (holding..., ca. 1953
      - Women washing dishes and pots and pans in an..., ca. 1953
      - An old man in a black hat and glasses sits at a..., ca. 1953
      - A man with a hat squats against a wall while..., ca. 1953
      - A young woman in a black wrap, holding a basket..., ca. 1953
      - Two male Mariachi musicians playing a wooden..., ca. 1953
      - A rocky ruin site in the foreground, and a..., ca. 1953
      - An old man wearing a hat and draped clothing..., ca. 1953
      - Stepped structure of a ruin...., ca. 1953
      - Rooftops of a village with mountains in the..., ca. 1953
      - Rooftops of a village with a church in the center,..., ca. 1953
      - A small boy and girl in a village with huts, palm..., ca. 1953
      - Courtyards in a the village with people scattered..., ca. 1953
      - Man walking his bicycle on an empty sidewalk,..., ca. 1953
      - Boulevard scene with cars and a median with a..., ca. 1953
      - A tower of a church, with a cross at the top...., ca. 1953
      - Structure apart of a church...., ca. 1953
      - Church and courtyard with a metal gate with the..., ca. 1953
      - Wall of an old ruined building...., ca. 1953
      - San Agostino Church. "The oldest church, erected..., ca. 1953
      - A modern designed church with a stone tower on the..., ca. 1953
      - Ornate façade of a building with sculpted figures..., ca. 1953
      - Courtyard with people in Mexico City. (Includes..., ca. 1953
      - A small church courtyard, or atrium, with trees...., ca. 1953
      - Capilla del Pocito (Chapel of the little well)...., ca. 1953
      - A cyprus tree and cross on a pillar with a snow-..., ca. 1953
      - Isla de Janitzio on the main island of Lake..., ca. 1953
      - Farmers walking in a field with an ox-cart pulling..., ca. 1953
      - Hillside town with houses...., ca. 1953
      - Fog in a mountain valley with a telephone pole in..., ca. 1953
      - A vista with a cross in the foreground...., ca. 1953
      - A vista with trees in the foreground...., ca. 1953
      - A vista with trees in the foreground...., ca. 1953
      - Ruins with stepped walls...., ca. 1953
      - Church...., ca. 1953
      - In Oaxaca, a short straw roof covers a structure..., ca. 1953
      - Portrait of an old man with white hair, wearing a..., ca. 1953
      - Courtyard with two figures walking. A sign reads..., ca. 1953
      - Church tower with a cross on the top and a bell to..., ca. 1953
      - Four birdcages mounted to the wall...., ca. 1953
      - Ruins: includes three brick chimneys...., ca. 1953
      - Old woman holding a cigarette wearing a button-..., ca. 1953
      - A corner of a room with dried flowers and corncobs..., ca. 1953
      - Portrait of an old man with white hair, wearing a..., ca. 1953
      - A wooden hut with clothes hanging over the slatted..., ca. 1953
      - Man walking down hill next to wooden cross..., ca. 1953
      - Church with two towers in Mexico City...., ca. 1953
      - Buses at a terminal or garage...., ca. 1953
      - Graves in a cemetery...., ca. 1953
      - A quiet market scene with stalls and people..., ca. 1953
      - A traffic guard with cars and men walking next to..., ca. 1953
      - Tall building under construction. (Typed German..., ca. 1953
      - Capilla del Pocito (Chapel of the little well)...., ca. 1953
      - "Coconut harvest near Acapulco." Coconuts laid out..., ca. 1953
      - Cacti and aloe with a snow-capped mountain in the..., ca. 1953
      - White modern canapy-esque structure. (German text..., ca. 1953
      - Cliffs and houses by the coastline...., ca. 1953
      - Capilla del Pocito (Chapel of the little well)...., ca. 1953
      - Town with a church...., ca. 1953
      - Church dome...., ca. 1953
      - Teotihuacan temple, Pyramids of the Sun and the..., ca. 1953
      - Teotihuacan temple, Pyramids of the Sun and the..., ca. 1953
      - A church tower with a cross at the top of it...., ca. 1953
      - Masks and half-size figures leaning against a..., ca. 1953
      - Figure on upright stone slab...., ca. 1953
      - Three young children in hats walking by the steps..., ca. 1953
      - Teotihuacan temple, Pyramids of the Sun and the..., ca. 1953
      - Interior of the Teotihuacan temple, Pyramid of the..., ca. 1953
      - Figurines in the window. (Backside text reads:..., ca. 1953
    - New York City: contact prints (1-4), Undated (Box 36 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 6-9)
    - New York City (1-2), Undated (Box 36 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 10-11)
    - New York City (3-11), Undated (Box 37 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 1-9)
    - New York City (12-20), Undated (Box 38 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 1-9)
    - New York City (21-30), Undated (Box 39 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 1-10)
    - New York City: Bowery, Undated; 2 folders (Box 40 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 1-2)
    - New York City: Bronx Veteran's Hospital, Undated (Box 40 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 3)
    - New York City: Coney Island (1-5), 1948 (Box 40 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 4-8)
    - New York City: Eagles and Lions (1-2), Undated (Box 40 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 9-10)
    - Paris, 1955 (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 1)
    - Provincetown, MA: contact prints, Undated (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 2)
    - Provincetown, MA (1-3), Undated (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 3-5)
    - Swarthmore, PA, Undated (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 6)
    - West Point Military Academy, NY, Undated (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 7)
  - Subject folders, 14.2
    - Americana - Architecture & Automobiles, Undated (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 8)
    - Amish families, Undated (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 9)
    - Animals, Undated (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 10)
    - Cemeteries, Undated (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 11)
    - Circus, Undated (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 12)
    - Factories, Undated (Box 41 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 13)
    - Farms and Rural Subjects, Undated (Box 42 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 1)
    - Fireworks, Undated (Box 42 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 2)
    - Flags, Undated (Box 42 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 3)
    - Flowers (1-3), Undated (Box 42 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 4-6)
    - Mannequins, Undated (Box 42 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 7)
    - Markets, Undated (Box 42 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 8)
    - Nature Scenes (1-3), Undated (Box 42 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 9-11)
    - Patterns, Undated (Box 43 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 1)
    - Portraits: Yamaoka, Françoise Sagan, Louis Peterson, Gina Lollobrigida, Baxter, Paul Ehrlich's widow & family, Salvador Dali, Gustav Gründgens, Undated (Box 43 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 2)
    - Portraits: children, Undated (Box 43 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 3)
    - Portraits: people, Undated (Box 43 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 4)
    - Portraits: women, Undated (Box 43 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 5)
    - Reflections (1-3), Undated (Box 43 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 6-8)
    - Shadows, Undated (Box 43 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 9)
    - Ships and Boats, Undated (Box 43 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 10)
    - Washlines, Undated (Box 43 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 11)
  - Personal photographs of Neugass and family, 1913-1976; 14.3
    - Early family photographs, 1913; 1921; Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 1)
    - Photo album, titled "Portraits with friends during travels as Boy Scout", ca. 1920s (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 2)
    - Photo album. Neugass in Greece, 1930s (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 3)
    - Neugass in Greece, 1931; 1934; Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 4)
    - Neugass, 1931; 1934; Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 5)
    - Neugass, 1939; Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 6)
    - Neugass, 1940 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 7)
    - Neugass, arrival in the U.S., 1942 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 8)
    - Neugass, photographs by Fred Stein, 1942 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 9)
    - Fritz and Lotte Neugass, 1948 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 10)
    - Neugass, photo by Joseph Breitenbach, 1950 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 11)
    - Neugass, photos by Eugene Moses, 1955 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 12)
    - Fritz and Lotte Neugass party, photos and negatives by Fred Stein, 1955 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 13)
    - Fritz and Lotte Neugass, 1955; Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 14)
    - Fritz and Lotte Neugass. Negatives, 1955; 1956; Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 15)
    - Pencil sketch of Neugass by Douglas Lazauris, 1957 March 9 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 16)
    - Neugass, photo by John Lefebre, 1970 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 17)
    - Fritz and Lotte Neugass, 1970s; Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 18)
      Neugass, photo by Sonja Bullaty.
    - Fritz and Lotte Neugass, photographs by Raimondo Borea, 1973; 1976 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 19)
    - Fritz and Lotte Neugass, 1974; 1977 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 20)
    - Neugass, photos by Lil Picard, 1976 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 21)
    - Fritz Neugass. A Memorial Meeting of His Friends, Goethe House, 1979 October 15 (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 22)
    - Self-portrait negative, Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 23)
    - Neugass, City Patrol Corps, Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 24)
    - Fritz and Lotte Neugass, early photo, Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 25)
    - Neugass, color negatives, Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 26)
    - Portrait photos including by Thomas Feist, Kempe, Fred Stein, J. Feneyrol, Gerard Oppenheimer, Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 27)
    - Photographs of Fritz Neugass photograph exhibit, Undated (Box 44 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 28)
    - Mounted photographs, predominantly Mediterranean and New York City scenes, 1930-1950 (Box 45-48 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass))
    - Greece, Italy, American Southwest, ca. 1930-1950; Oversized photographs (Box 49 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass))
    - Veteran's Hospital, Nature, Flowers, Trees, People, Industry, 1940s; Oversized photographs (Box 50 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass))
    - New York City, Coney Island, Provincetown, 1940s; Oversized photographs (Box 51 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass))
    - Fritz Neugass mounted photographs (19) for Hypo-Hounds exhibit, Users Club, NY, 1940s (Box 52 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass))
    - Mexico Exhibit, American Museum of Natural History, 1954 March 04-1954 March 28 (Box 53-55 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass))
    - Negatives of Neugass' photographs, Undated (Box 56-59 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass))
    - Scrapbook by Fritz Neugass with clippings and original texts of articles, most from 1959 (Box 60 (14-Photographs by Fritz Neugass), Folder 1)
- Photographs by Other Artists, 15
  Photographs by Werner Cohnitz, Eliot Eliosofon, Walter Laeubli, Gjon Mili, Arnold Newman, Edward Steichen, and other unidentified photographers. Most of these pictures were taken in Europe shortly after World War II and include outdoor scenes, and posed images of models.
  Arranged roughly by subject.
  - Magnum Photos, Inc. Photographs by: George Rodger, Werner Bischof, Robert Capa, Fenno Jacobs, Carl Perutz, Homer Page, Henri Cartier-Bresson, David Seymour, Ernst Haas, Undated (Box 61 (15-Photographs by Other Artists), Folder 1)
  - Magazine articles photographed by: Elliott Erwitt, Ernst Haas, Werner Bischof, David Seymour, Undated (Box 61 (15-Photographs by Other Artists), Folder 2)
  - Leonard McCombe photographs (14), Undated (Box 61 (15-Photographs by Other Artists), Folder 3)
  - Walter Laeubli photographs (33), Undated (Box 61 (15-Photographs by Other Artists), Folder 4)
  - Anonymous photograph, Undated (Box 61 (15-Photographs by Other Artists), Folder 5)
  - Eliot Elisofon photograph, Undated (Box 61 (15-Photographs by Other Artists), Folder 6)
  - Gion Mili photograph, Undated (Box 61 (15-Photographs by Other Artists), Folder 7)
  - Edward Steichen photograph, Undated (Box 61 (15-Photographs by Other Artists), Folder 8)
  - Arnold Newman photograph, Undated (Box 61 (15-Photographs by Other Artists), Folder 9)
  - Werner Cohnitz photographs (7), Undated (Box 61 (15-Photographs by Other Artists), Folder 10)
- Series 16: Sotheby Parke-Bernet auction catalogs, 1938-1979; 14 archival boxes (Box 62-75 (Fritz Neugass Papers))
  This series contains Sotheby Parke-Bernet auction catalogs dating from 1938-1979. A complete list of the catalogs is located in Box 62. The catalogs have been listed by date, sale catalog number, with brief description. Neugass attended most of the auctions represented by the catalogs, and each catalog is accompanied by price lists resulting from the auctions. The catalogs are also annotated by Neugass. Neugass wrote articles on many of the auctions he attended, the texts of which are contained in Series 3.
  Arranged chronologically, listed by date, sale catalog number, with brief description. A complete list of the catalogs is located in Box 62.